

Gonzalo Varela

Developer Sr.

Phone: +54 911 - 6864 - 0435

gonzalo.varela1981@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/gonzalo-varela-85815320/

Summary

I am a software developer with experience in SQL Postgres + PostGIS databases and Python + Django. Specialized in GIS software with a working experience implementing and maintaining Geoserver and Geonode platforms. I had also work extensively with Leafletjs, MapboxGL and VectorTile server. I am open to work as part of a team or individually.

Key Technologies

Python + Django, PostgreSQL, Geoserver, Geonetwork, GeoJSON, PHP, QGIS

Languages

English - Intermediate

Habilities and Technologies

PostgreSQL, SQL/PL-SQL

PostGIS

Python + Django

Geoserver, Geonetwork, Geonode, QGIS

PHP

Bash, CSS, jQuery, HTML 5, LeafLetJS

Problem solving

Linux, Windows, MySQL, Programming, Code Igniter (mvc framework PHP)

Development, Web Services

Education / Courses

UNTREF University (2019 – Present day)

Bachelor in GIS (Geographic Information System)

FIUBA graduates center (2018)

Python for developers

FOSS4G-AR

Geonetwork Introduction (2018)

Advanced Geonetwork – Code Personalization (2019) Advanced Geoserver – Cluster and Load Balancing over Docker (2019) PGRouting (2018)

Educación IT

Java Essentials (2010) PHP Web Services (2011)

High School - ET Nº 28 REPUBLICA FRANCESA

Technical degree in electronics 1994 - 1999

Work Experience

Technical Lead / Developer Sr/ SIG Consultant at SSPPBE - GCBA (Buenos Aires City government) April 2021 – Present day

In April 2021 I assumed the role of both Developer and Technical Leader not only for the experience in Geographic Information Systems but also due to my abilities to anticipate and solve problems

April 2020 - Present day

I started as a Developer Ssr. and began to assume a Sr. role slowly, getting involved in models design, code revision and helping pushing forward halted processes in pair coding sessions.

Some highlight projects are:

- 1 Back-end design (API-Taxi con Django + Postgres + PostGIS) https://ruteo.usig.buenosaires.gob.ar/pie/viaroute?loc=-34.4873995,-58.684607&loc=-34.5009963,-58.6760981&instructions=true
- 2 Debug and Expand functionalities API Catastro (Python + Django) https://epok.buenosaires.gob.ar/catastro/
- 3 Functionality updates API Ciudad3D (Python + Django) https://ciudad3d.buenosaires.gob.ar
- 4 Back-end update (Gestor de Datos Geográficos con Django + Postgres + PostGIS) https://epok.buenosaires.gob.ar/pub/mapa/mapaescolar/establecimientos_educativos/
- 5 Implementation and Maintenance Vector Tile Server (Python + sqlite)
- 6 Documentation and Tutorial reviews

- 7 Docker images creation from scratch or update
- 8 File uploads and metadata updates automation to Open Data Portal (python + CKAN)
- 9 Geospatial Data analysis (PostGIS + QGIS, adress normalization, 3DCity visualization)
- 10 Process normalization (Map of crime) https://mapa.seguridadciudad.gob.ar/

Developer / Freelance Consultant

March 2015 - March 2020

I worked independently for a few years in challenging and innovating projects.

Some remarkable companies and/or institutions I had the opportunity to work include:

- National Institute of Geography (Branch of Defense department)
- ScanTerra S.A. (Geographic data analysis for Agriculture)

Some highlight projects I had participated on:

- 1 Map servers: Installation, monitoring and maintenance of map servers and georeferenced data under **Geoserver** technology. Implementation in diverse ecosystems such as **Docker**, JAVA Servlet under **Apache Tomcat** or compiled **Jetty** environment.
- 2 Interactive Maps: Interactive map development for elementary and high school students usage. It allows students to perform measures, draw lines and write notations on blank maps to be saved as PDF files or printed on paper. http://mapasescolares.ign.gob.ar/
- 3 Geographic Data Publication: Geonode Installation, migration and maintenance. http://qhapaqnan.ign.gob.ar/
- 4 Rancher (Docker orchestration) The challenge was to discover every micro-service of a complete and vast stack to achieve 3 separate tasks:
 - Identify both github and dockerhub repositories for each stack component.
 - Identify every technology integrated in the system and define which technical profiles where required for the next development stages.
 - Write and expand documentation for every micro-service and pipeline.
- 5 Processes analysis: Deployment process analysis to increase stability and reliability, accommodate backup instances, rollbacks and other desired improvements.
- 6 Web Page data capture: Data capture automation using Selenium + Python technologies, it extracts data which only can be retrieved by navigating a web page. Tasks include
 - user authentication
 - menu navigation,
 - file downloads and migrate data from downloaded files into a database.
- 7 Geoserver / Geonode instalation and fine tuning for heavy load.
 - http://wms.ign.gob.ar
 - http://qhapaqnan.ign.gob.ar
- 8 Joomla! / Drupal components adaptation.

Devops at TSOFT (for TELECOM S.A.)

- SeleniumHQ/ Javascript / Bash / SOAPUI developer with assertions-driven regression detection
- 2 Jenkins administration and unit test configuration
- 3 Gantt design and monitoring for QA environments assembly
- 4 Coordination between various Software Factories, deployment areas and QA teams.
- 5 Linux user creation, disk monitoring, bash scripting
- 6 Cross applications messaging coordination
- 7 Infrastructure delivery coordination

Developer Jr at 4IT (for Banking client)

December 2012 - August 2014 (21 Months)

- 1. ETLs scripting
- 2. MySQL administration
- 3. MySQL stored procedures and data modeling
- 4. Banking data analyss, product results vs global results
- 5. Web aplication design, html + jQuery + bootstrap

Developer at TECENG GAMING

December 2011 - November 2012 (12 Months)

- 1. Data migration between SQL databases
- 2. Database administration, data validation
- 3. User Manual and Administrator Manual manufacture
- 4. Data analysis using PostgreSQL

Developer Jr and Help Desk at TECENG GAMING

March 2010 - December 2011 (22 Months)

Bash Scripting
User support
PostgreSQL Database administration
Data analysis
User support

Processes analysis at Arwen

March 2003 - January 2010 (83 Months)

Processes automation Visual Basic developer MS-Excel support

Support at Tecnet S.A.

March 2001 - February 2003 (22 Months)

MS-Windows Help Desk Lotus Notes Help Desk

Help Desk at Wober y Asoc.

March 1999 - April 2001 (26 Months)

- 1. Help Desk
- 2. Computer and Printers repair
- 3. Network wires installation

Gonzalo Varela

Gis Developer | Technical Lead

gonzalo.varela1981@gmail.com



3 personas han recomendado a Gonzalo

"Recomiendo a Gonzalo Varela por ser una persona capaz en el sentido Laboral y Humano, ya que se integra de manera muy rápida al grupo y posee facilidad de aprendizaje, es un muy buen trabajador."

— Alfredo Cabezas, Técnico, Tecnet, ha trabajado directamente con Gonzalo en Tecnet S.A..

"Gonzalo es un excelente profesional y correcta persona, tuve la suerte de trabajar con el en distintos proyectos. Maneja muy bien las relaciones interpersonal adaptándose muy bien a los distintos grupos de trabajo, tiene facilidad para de aprendizaje."

— Bruno J. Bosco Tmanager IT ISSUING PROCESSING supervisó a Gonzalo en 4IT..

"Es un gusto trabajar con Gonzalo. Se ha hecho cargo de la coordinación técnica del equipo de desarrollo de Ingeniería de Datos con mucha idoneidad, no sólo desde su conocimiento de las tecnologías y de las soluciones que desarrolla y mantiene el área, sino también desde el abordaje humano del equipo. Es un equipo que ha encarado procesos complejos de implementaciones, de resolución de incidentes y de desarrollo de soluciones en medio de una transición de referentes y bajo gran presión, y Gonzalo ha sabido aportar claridad, eficacia y buena coordinación de los colaboradores. Confío plenamente en su criterio técnico, y me da gusto compartir el día a día de trabajo con él."

— Rocío Marcalain, Directora General de Arquitectura de Datos, ha ocupado Gonzalo en Tecnet S.A..